Hello everyone, welcome back
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine
and today Marco we're
talking about something
that I know you're a big fan of.
I am, we're talking about
computer games, video games.
Woohoo!
So yeah, we're going
to be looking at some
vocabulary and phrases
related to computer games
and video games and this is actually
a request from one of our users.
Awesome, so before
we get started, we do
have the name of the game
that we're going to look at.
So let's listen to that in
today's vocabulary preview.
vocabulary preview.
All right, so the game that we're going
to preview today is called Counter Strike.
Okay, so first you have a strike or an
attack, then you have a counter strike.
So that's an opposite attack
or something like that, right?
So it's a reaction to the
first thing that happens.
So you hit me and my
counter strike as I hit you back.
And this game is
actually very, very popular
all over the world because many players
are able to compete at the same time.
So it's a shooting game,
you shoot each other,
you are the terrorists
and then the other
team is like the police
or the army or whatever.
Wow, sounds really exciting.
Well we're going to
learn more about the
specific vocab that goes
with computer games
and video games in a minute, but
first let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Mark, where have you been?
I've been calling you all morning.
I have been playing computer games.
What?
So you blew me off
yesterday and today over a
stupid video game, what game is so important
that you have no time for me anymore?
What are you playing?
It's called Counter Strike, it's a first
person shooter game, it's awesome.
It's a multiplayer game
where you can go online
and compete against
players from all over the world.
You've been wasting your
time on this, I can't believe it.
It doesn't even look fun or challenging.
My laptop is on my bed.
If you think it's so easy then
get online and try to beat me.
Fine.
Damn it.
How are you killing me with a single shot?
It's not fair.
I don't want to play anymore.
Let's go get something to eat.
Can you bring me something?
I'm totally hooked on this game.
Alright we're back so there
was some really interesting
vocab here and so let's look
at it now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay so what kind of a
game was this, Marco?
Alright this game
was a FPS or also in the
dialogue we heard a
first person shooter game.
So our users might have
heard this phrase first person
before because it's a
grammar term in many ways.
We talk about I, I do
this, I can sing as the
first person but we're
talking about games
first person shooter means
that what you do you're
doing as if you were
the character in the game.
Right so even the way
that you're looking at
the game it seems like you're looking
through the eyes of the character.
Okay so you don't see the body,
you are the body of the person.
So first person shooter
so shooter obviously
means that this is a
shooting game what you
do is you pull the
trigger, swim shoot people.
Exactly and as we
mentioned a lot of players
are able to compete against each
other so it's called a multiplayer game.
So multi is a prefix, it goes at the beginning
of a word in English that means many.
So you could hear
multicolored or multiethnic
and the meaning of
this is that there are many
different colors or
many different ethnicities
or in this case multiplayer many
different players at the same time.
Exactly so in this in
this game you can many
players can play whether it's in a local
area network or online over the internet.
Cool so you actually have to have the
internet right when you're doing this because
you're using many different computers
so they have to be connected to each other.
Right so and that's our next
word you go online in order to play.
Okay so online you've heard before online
means on the internet but in this case the
action of using the
internet is called going
online so I want to go
online to read my email.
Right or I can't go online
I don't have a connection.
My mom won't let me
go online I'm in trouble.
Alright so this is the
way that you use it you go
online in order to use
the internet you go online.
Very interesting.
Well the last word we've
got here in language
takeaway is very
important one we talk about
video games because many people are in this
situation they're hooked on video games.
Right so if you are
hooked on a video game
or you are hooked on
anything it means you're
kind of addicted or you're very
very interested in something.
Exactly so I'm hooked
on the TV show True
Blood I love to watch
it and I love I every day
around home so I can't watch it but is
there a game that you're hooked on Marko?
Currently I am hooked on a
game called Guitar Hero Metallica.
Ooh fun.
Yeah it's really fun.
When I borrowed your PS3 I
was hooked on bad company.
Their great games is very easy
to get hooked on video games.
Too easy.
Alright so that's all
the words we have for
language takeaway
why don't we listen to our
dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit.
Mark where have you been
I've been calling you all morning.
I have been playing computer games.
What?
So you blew me off
yesterday and today over
a stupid video game what game is so important
that you have no time for me anymore?
What are you playing?
It's called Counter
Strike it's a first person
shooter game it's
awesome it's a multiplayer
game where you can go online and compete
against players from all over the world.
I've been wasting
your time on this I can't
believe it it doesn't even
look fun or challenging.
My laptop is on my bed if you think it's
so easy then get online and try to beat me.
Fine.
Damn it how are you
killing me with a single shot
it's not fair I don't want
to play anymore let's
go get something to eat can you bring me
something I'm totally hooked on this game.
We're back and we have
a couple phrases that
we want to look at
specifically two phrases
so let's look at those
now and fluency builder.
Fluency Builder.
So what's the deal you
blew me off yesterday
and now you're not
even going to say sorry.
Alright so blew me off
what do you what do you
mean when you say you
blew me off yesterday.
Okay so let's take a
look at the the infinitive
version of this phrase
so to blow someone
off and they all go
together it's a fixed phrase.
And this means to have
an appointment with
someone but to not go
all right so we had a date
planned but he blew
me off what a jerk so
he didn't go but I
went did he tell you that
he wasn't going to
go no okay no so it's
it's a surprise it's like
you expect someone
to come meet you or
do something with you
but they don't plant
they don't say anything
and they don't go so
there's another word
very similar to this
when it and it's to stand
someone up right
exactly so he stood me up
he didn't come he blew
me off okay very good
alright and what's our next phrase to waste
your time alright so the girlfriend in this
case was like you're
wasting your time on
these video games that
means you're not getting
anything out of this
you're not benefiting
it means that you could
spend your time doing
other things okay so
if you're wasting your
time on video games
you're not being productive
exactly so anything so
your mother might say
to you when you're
a kid don't waste your
time on games you
should be studying okay or
he wastes a lot of
time watching TV that's
a common problem all right so let's listen
to the dialogue again real fast and we'll
go back in a bit mark
where have you been
I've been calling you
all morning I have been
playing computer games what so you blew me
off yesterday and today over a stupid video
game what game is so
important that you have
no time for me anymore
what are you playing
it's called Counter
Strike it's a first person
shooter game it's
awesome it's a multiplayer
game where you can
go online and compete
against players from
all over the world you've
been wasting your time
on this I can't believe
it it doesn't even
look fun or challenging
my laptop is on my
bed if you think it's so
easy then get online
and try to beat me fine
damn it how are you killing me with a single
shot it's not fair I don't want to play
anymore let's go get
some of the eat can you
bring me something
I'm totally hooked on this
game all right so we
talked about you know
being hooked on TV
shows and video games but
this is actually a very big problem in some
Asian country specifically right I've heard
that actually I heard
that in Japan Korea and
China specifically
there are psychological
treatment centers for kids who are addicted
to gaming and so there's a big thing in the
news in China recently
where where there are
parents who are
sending their kids to this
treatment center rehab
rehab for games and that
actually they found
out that the rehab center
didn't know what they were doing and they
were giving the kids electro shock therapy
to get them off games
really so the parents
took their kids back
that's scary it is scary
I guess it's a very popular thing in Asian
countries specifically right to play online
to go online there's a lot of other factors
that that influence this but but I think it
is like everything
in the X in excess is
dangerous this is true
and actually some people
have been using this addiction to be a
productive use of their time so you have some
people who play a game
called World of Warcraft
and they win money
and they sell things
to other players all over the world so you
have these kids in America buying toys and
like shields and gold
from kids in for example
Indonesia and the kid
in Indonesia is making
money right right
and also if they're really
good they go on to
become professional gamers
and compete in world
competitions and and
also test out new video
games so yeah it has
its advantages as well
can you imagine what
your business card would
look like professional
gamer professional
gamer alright that's all the
time we have for today
we hope you enjoyed this
lesson and of course if
you have any questions
comments or doubts please
come to our website englishpot.
com and we'll see you guys
there until next time everyone bye